PETR KOVAR

PERSONAL DETAILS

Email: pmkovar@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/pmkovar

GitHub: github.com/pmkovar/



SUMMARY

My expertise lies in technical communication, and project and program management, with a focus on delivering clear, effective documentation. I'm experienced in community management and open source software development, connecting the community and corporate contributors.

Additionally, I'm skilled in technical translation, working within open source translation communities to make software and documentation accessible worldwide.

WORK EXPERIENCE

8/2018–9/2023 **Documentation Program Manager, Red Hat**

Brno, Czechia

- Played a key role in reestablishing and transforming a writing group for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization into an agile team.
- · Developed new workflows and mentored team members to ensure their success in an agile environment.
- · Oversaw release management, task planning, and tracking.
- Integrated 15+ Kubernetes and OpenShift-based tools and the Red Hat Developer Program projects into a unified, Jira-centered documentation project, bringing together 25+ writers under a cohesive framework.
- Project Management · Program Management · Agile & Waterfall Methodologies · Task Assignment · Jira · Cloud-Native Applications · DevOps · Kubernetes · OpenShift

3/2015–8/2018 Senior Technical Writer, Red Hat

Brno, Czechia

- Developed a content strategy for single-sourcing Red Hat Enterprise Linux desktop documentation, ensuring seamless delivery across both community and enterprise products.
- Contributed to transforming CloudForms content into topic-based documentation, utilizing a new docs-as-code toolchain built on Asciidoc.
- $\bullet \ \ Content \ Strategy \cdot Continuous \ Integration \ and \ Continuous \ Delivery \ (CI/CD) \cdot Topic-based \ Authoring \cdot Markdown \cdot Sphinx \cdot AsciiDoc$

4/2011-3/2015

Technical Writer II

Brno, Czechia

- Developed content for key areas of Linux platform and cloud products, including package management, identity and access management, and desktop on Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
- Researched documentation topics by analyzing technical specifications, reviewing source code, interviewing Subject Matter Experts, and building test environments.
- Served as the documentation lead for the desktop area, establishing single-source workflows and collaborating with the GNOME and Fedora documentation and translation communities.
- ullet Linux \cdot DocBook \cdot XML \cdot Technical Writing \cdot Bash \cdot Git \cdot Single Sourcing \cdot Content Management

PROJECTS

8/2017-3/2019

Documentation Project Team Lead, OpenStack

- Elected Project Team Lead of the OpenStack Documentation Project by the OpenStack community.
- · Responsible for documentation release management, community engagement, writers mentorship.
- Represented the documentation project by running documentation sessions at OpenStack summits and Project Team Gatherings.
- As a writer, maintained Red Hat-specific content provided by the OpenStack Documentation Project.
- Collaborated in the building and running of the OpenStack documentation site.
- Co-maintained the RDO project site, using the Middleman framework.
- $\ \, \textbf{Release Management} \cdot \textbf{Coaching \& Mentoring} \cdot \textbf{Community Management} \cdot \textbf{Community Engagement} \cdot \textbf{Community Outreach} \\$

8/2017–Present

Lead, GNOME Documentation Project

- Lead a team of community writers to create comprehensive user, sysadmin, and developer documentation for official GNOME releases.
- · Oversaw maintenance, issue resolution, and release management of documentation packages.
- Contributed to the information architecture for both desktop and online documentation.
- Organized and facilitated documentation meetups, workshops, and hackfests to engage and support the broader GNOME community.

4/2010-Present

Member of the GNOME Translation Project Coordination Team, GNOME

- Collaborate with the Coordination Team to manage the l10n.gnome.org platform, overseeing issue resolution and user management for 50+ GNOME translation teams.
- Approved code freeze exceptions as part of the GNOME release process.
- Organized community meetups for the GNOME translation community at annual GUADEC conferences.

2007-3/2018

Czech Translation Team Coordinator, GNOME Translation Project

- Coordinated a team of community translators. Responsible for onboarding and training, ticket reporting and escalation, and delivering translations for official GNOME releases as well as third-party projects hosted by GNOME, such as GIMP.
- Organized meetups for Czech translators across various open-source projects under the L10n.cz platform, fostering collaboration and knowledge sharing within the community.

EDUCATION

2015–2018 Masaryk University

Brno, Czechia

• Bachelor of Arts — BA, Information and Library Studies

CERTIFICATES

• Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), issued 9/2012

LANGUAGES

- English full professional proficiency
- Czech native proficiency